Guide to the Camp family papers, 1817-1953.
Camp family papers, 1817-1953.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Camp family papers, 1817-1953.
891
Camp family.
4.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, accounts, diaries, family stories, postcards, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes papers of the related Osborn and Camp families.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
John G. Camp was chief of the Quartermaster Dept. of the Army of the Niagara in the War of 1812, a member of the Ohio Legislature, and U.S. Marshall at Tallahassee, Fla. His son, Jacob Andrus Camp (1823-1900) was paymaster in Kentucky and Tennessee during the Civil War and a special agent for the U.S. Treasury Dept. Their families lived in Buffalo, N.Y. and Sandusky, Ohio.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes papers of the related Osborn and Camp families.
Osborn family papers include letters from Ebeneezer Francis Osborn describing his life as a clerk in the firm of Osborn and Young, New York City, a serious yellow fever epidemic in New York City, a voyage (1825-1828) to Rio de Janeiro, Valparaiso, Arica, Lima, and other South American cities, trading opportunities, social, political, and military activities, and the attitude of the people of Lima toward the intended visit of Simon Bolivar; a series of letters (1831-1839) describing social life in New England and public opinion on the death of Ralph Waldo Emerson's wife; a series (1840-1848) describing life, a flour business and store in the river town of Louisiana, Mo.; a series describing life in Sandusky, Oh.; and a letter (1856) describing a Northerner's reactions to life in the South.
Correspondence, accounts, and other papers of John G. Camp; Jacob A. Camp's daily reports as special agent and letters of instruction (1878-1884) on investigations of customhouses, complaints against Federal officials, claims against the Federal Government, and bids for Federal appropriations; accounts (1871) for the Oil & Guano Company, Sandusky, Ohio; diary and household expenses of Elizabeth Francis Osborn Camp (1835-1920), wife of Jacob A. Camp; family stories by Anna (Camp) Edwards; postcards from various European cities and from Japan and Russia; and material relating to the Civil War, to Federal patronage, and to life in Buffalo, Sandusky, Florida, New York City, Washington, D.C., and the South after the Civil War. Correspondents include Charles J. Folger, Rutherford B. Hayes, Thomas S. Jessup, Winfield Scott, John Sherman, and John Tyler. Includes documents signed by James Madison, John Tyler, Andrew Johnson and Abraham Lincoln
SUBJECTS
Names:
Camp family.; Camp, Elizabeth Francis Osborn.; Camp, Jacob Andrus, 1823-1900.; Camp, John G.; Edwards, Anna Camp.; Folger, Charles J. (Charles James), 1818-1884.; Hayes, Rutherford Birchard, 1822-1893.; Jessup, Thomas J.; Johnson, Andrew; Lincoln, Abraham, 1744-1786; Madison, James; Scott, Winfield, 1786-1866.; Sherman, John, 1823-1900.; Tyler, John, 1790-1862.; Ohio.General Assembly.; Oil & Guano Company (Sandusky, Oh.); Osborn and Young (New York, N.Y.); United States. Army. Quartermaster Corps.; United States. Dept. of the Treasury.
Subjects:
Custom houses--United States.; Family--New York (State)--Buffalo.; Family--Ohio--Sandusky.; Patronage, Political.; Women's diaries.; General stores--Missouri--Louisiana.; Yellow fever--New York (N.Y.); Flour and feed trade--Missouri--Louisiana.
Places:
United States--Social life and customs.; South America--Description and travel.; United States--History--War of 1812.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Buffalo (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.; Sandusky (Oh.)--Social life and customs.; Florida--Social life and customs.; New York (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.; Japan--Pictorial works.; Russia--Pictorial works.; Europe--Pictorial works.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Postcards.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Osborn family papers
  - Correspondence, 1804-1819 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1825-1828 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1831-1839 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1842-1847 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1848-1855 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1856-1859, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II. Camp family papers
  - Correspondence, 1814-1835 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1836-1840 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1843-1846 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Legal brief, Oct. 24, 1848-1852 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1853-1855 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1856-1859 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-June, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: July-Aug., 1861 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Sept.-Oct., 1861 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Nov., 1861 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Dec., 1861 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Feb., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Mar.-Apr., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: May-Aug., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Sept., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Oct., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Nov.-Dec., 1862 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Apr., 1865 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: May-Dec., 1865 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Mar., 1866 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Apr.-Dec., 1866 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1868 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1873-1874 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Mar., 1876 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Apr.-Dec., 1876 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Feb.-Sept., 1878 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Dec., 1878 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Sept., 1879 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Dec., 1879 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Jan., 1880 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Feb., 1880 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Mar., 1880 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Apr., 1880 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: May, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: June-July, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Aug.-Sept., 1880 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Nov., 1880 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Dec., 1880 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Jan., 1881 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Feb., 1881 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Mar.-Apr., 1881 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: May, 1881 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: June-July, 1881 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Aug.-Sept., 1881 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Oct., 1881 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Nov.-Dec., 1881 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Jan., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Feb., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Mar., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Apr., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: May, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: June, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: July, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Aug.-Sept., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Nov., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Dec., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Jan., 1883 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Feb., 1883 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Mar., 1883 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Apr., 1883 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: May, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: June, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: July, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Aug., 1883 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Sept., 1883 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Oct., 1883 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Nov., 1883 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Dec., 1883 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Jan., 1884 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Feb., 1884 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Mar.-May, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: June-Dec., 1884 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Feb.-Mar., 1885 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Apr., 1885 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: May-Nov., 1885 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Apr.-June, 1886 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: July, 1886 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Aug.-Dec., 1886 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Apr., 1887 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: May-Sept., 1887 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Dec., 1887 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Apr., 1888 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: May-Aug., 1888 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Sept.-Oct., 1888 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Nov.-Dec., 1888 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Jan., 1889 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Feb., 1889 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Mar., 1889 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence: Apr., 1889 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence: May, 1889 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: June, 1889 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
  - Correspondence: July, 1889 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Aug., 1889 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Sept.-Oct., 1889 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Nov.-Dec., 1889 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Jan., 1890 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Feb.-Mar., 1890 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Apr.-May, 1890 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: June-Aug., 1890 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Sept.-Oct., 1890 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Nov.-Dec., 1890 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Feb., 1891 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Mar.-July, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Aug.-Dec., 1891 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Feb., 1892 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Mar.-Apr., 1892 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: May-June, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: July-Nov., 1892 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Dec., 1892 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-May, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: June-Dec., 1893 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Mar., 1894 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Apr., 1894 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: May, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: June-Sept., 1894 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Nov., 1894 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Dec., 1894 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Jan., 1895 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Feb., 1895 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Mar., 1895 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Apr., 1895 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: May-June, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: July-Aug., 1895 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Sept., 1895 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Dec., 1895 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-June, 1896 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: July-Dec., 1896 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Feb.-Sept., 1897 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Dec., 1897 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-June, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Aug.-Dec., 1898 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Feb., 1899 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: May-Sept., 1899 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Dec., 1899 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Sept., 1900 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Dec., 1900 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Apr., 1901 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: May-June, 1901 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: July, 1901 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Aug., 1901 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Sept., 1901 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Oct.-Nov., 1901 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Apr.-May, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: June-Aug., 1906 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Sept.-Nov., 1906 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-Apr., 1908 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: May-Sept., 1908 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1911-1916 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1917-1939 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 10, Folder 8-19)
- Series III. Camp-Osborn family papers
  - John G. Camp Papers, 1814-1853 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "A Little History of Politics for the Past Twenty-five Years from 1855" manuscript and typescript by Jacob A. Camp, 1880 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Texas Lands, 1858-1897 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Presidential Inaugurations, 1869, 1881 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Patents - Jacob Camp, 1876, 1884 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Office of Special Agent Jacob A. Camp Reports of Daily Employment, 1878-1881 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Office of Special Agent Jacob A. Camp Reports of Daily Employment, 1882-1883 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Osborn - Executor's Accounts, 1893 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript draft "Money - Silver - Notes" [?], 1894 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - William Wyatt Camp, 1894, 1905-1915 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Gold, 1896-1900 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Cemetery Papers, 1851, 1900-1902 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Legal Documents, 1892, 1903, 1920, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Marshall Field and Company - Miss A. R. Camp, 1907 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Elizabeth F. Camp bank statements, 1907-1914 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - "Out of Old Virginia and New England" the story of Jacob Andrus Camp, 1823-1900 and Elizabeth Osborn Camp, 1835-1929, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Camp family genealogy (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Francis-Whitmore families genealogy (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Travel miscellany (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Miscellany, 1851-1873 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Miscellany (Box 11, Folder 21-24)
  - Newspaper clippings - "History", 1880's (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper clippings - "Biographical", 1880's (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1880's (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1880's (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 11, Folder 29-32)
  - Military Order of the Loyal Legion of the United States, 1893, 1895 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Picture postal cards of United States, Japan, Italy and Germany (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 3 photograph albums (Box 12)
  - Photographs of Osborn and Camp family members, and others, also 2 silhouettes; calling cards (Box 12)
  - Journals, diaries, notebooks, day books, 1852-1923 (Box 13)
  - Commissions and appointments of John G. Camp, Jacob A. Camp, Erskine M. Camp, 1812-1868 (Folder 1)
    Includes documents signed by James Madison, John Tyler, Andrew Johnson and Abraham Lincoln
  - 3 maps: Sandusky, Ohio, 1818, 1852 (Folder ?)
  - Certificate: Order of the Loyal Legion of the United States, 1896 (Folder ?)
  - Photo negatives of genealogical material re: Osborn, Camp, Francis, Whitmore families; lot map (Folder 2)
  - Indenture, 1814 (Folder 3)
  - Royal Arch Masons degree, 1817 (Folder 3)
  - Bounty Land Grant, 1856 (Folder 3)
  - Honorable Discharge, 1889 (Folder 3)
- Series IV. Additional Camp family correspondence
  - Letters (5 items, 1828-1842) to Maj. John G. Camp
    - From O. Follett, Buffalo, to JGC, Albany, NY, Mar. 15, 1828 (Box -, Folder -)
    - From Isaac Bell, New York, to JGC, Sandusky, Oct. 24, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - From brother, James, Weston, Lewis County, to JGC, Sandusky, Aug. 18, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - From son, Jacob A., Kenyon College, to JGC, Tallahassee, Florida, Mar. 24, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - From son, John, Jr., Sandusky, to JGC, Tallahassee, July 13, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters (2 items, 1836, 1842) to Mrs. John G. Camp
    - From sister, Sophia [?], Buffalo, Nov. 12, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - From Jacob A., Gambier, Nov. 13, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters (4 items, 1843-1844) to Jacob A. Camp, at Gambier, Ohio
    - From brother, John G., Jr., Sandusky, June 18, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - From sister, E.R.C.H. [?], Sandusky, Jan. 24, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - From brother, John, Sandusky, Mar. 18, [1844?] (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - From Charles H. Pitt, Baltimore, to JAC and John Boyd, June 22, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series V. Letters written by E. Francis Osborn from South America (originals of 7, transcripts of all 11)
  - Rio de Janeiro, July 27, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Valparaiso, Nov. 6, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Valparaiso, (sent by different ship), Nov. 6, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lima, Jan. 27, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lima, Jan. 30, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Valparaiso, Mar. 31, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Valparaiso, Apr. 18, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arica, July 18, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Valparaiso, Sept. 10, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lima, Nov. 13, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lima, Feb. 14, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 2)